Guide to the Trade catalogs collection.
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- P
  - Pratt and Whitney Aircraft Company (East Hartford, Conn.), 1936–1937; Uai +P8925; 2 volumes (Box 231, Folder 2879)
    Aircraft engines
  - Pratt and Whitney Company (Hartford, Conn.), 1892–1950; Uai +P8326; 5 volumes (Box 242, Folder 2958-2960)
    Gauges, machine tools, etc.
  - Pratt, B. G., Company, undated; Uai P887; 1 volume (Box 231, Folder 2872)
    "Scalecide" tree spray
  - Pratt, Charles (New York, N.Y.), 1869; Uai P8875; 1 volume (Box 231, Folder 2873)
    Oils, etc.
  - Precision Equipment Company (Chicago, Ill.), undated; Uai P911; 1 volume (Box 231, Folder 2880)
    Steel shelving
  - Precision Scientific Company (Chicago, Ill.), 1938; Uai +P912; 1 volume (Box 231, Folder 2881)
  - Prentice, James (New York, N.Y.), 1880; Uai P918; 1 volume (Box 231, Folder 2882)
    Civil engineering precision instruments
  - Prescott, J. B., and Son (Webster, Mass.), 1894; Uai P923; 2 volumes (Box 231, Folder 2883)
    Steel wall ties
  - Pressed Steel Car Company (Pittsburgh, Pa.), 1899; Uai +P926; 2 volumes (Box 231, Folder 2884)
    Steel train cars
  - Price, Theodore H., and Company (New York, N.Y.), 1910; Uai +P931; 1 volume (Box 231, Folder 2885)
    Cotton picker
  - Priess Radio Corporation (New York, N.Y.), 1927; Uai P933; 1 volume (Box 231, Folder 2886)
    Radios
  - Pritchard, Edwards and Company (Ithaca, N.Y.), 1891; Uai P939; 1 volume (Box 231, Folder 2887)
    Carriages, buggies, and platform wagons
  - Procter and Gamble Company, 1943; Uai +P941; 1 volume (Box 231, Folder 2888)
    Glycerin, fats, rubber goods, etc.
  - Proelss Sen. Seel. Söhne (Dresden, Germany), 1878; Uai P942; 1 volume (Box 231, Folder 2889)
    Fabric goods
  - Progressive Chemical Company (New Haven, Conn.), 1907; Uai P9426; 1 volume (Box 231, Folder 2890)
  - Progressive Stamp Album Company (St. Davids, Pa.), 1939–1940; Uai P943; 2 volumes (Box 231, Folder 2891)
    Stamp albums
  - Protecto Safety Appliance Company (Newark, N.J.), 1920; Uai P946; 2 volumes (Box 231, Folder 2892)
    Fume and gas masks
  - Proudfit Loose Leaf Company (Grand Rapids, Mich.), 1907–1910; Uai P947; 1 volume (Box 231, Folder 2893)
    Loose leaf devices
  - Providence Automobile Show (Providence, R.I.), 1908–1918; Uai P9475; 4 volumes (Box 231, Folder 2894)
    Automobiles, oils, etc.
  - Providence Steam Engine Company (Providence, R.I.), 1876; Uai P948; 1 volume (Box 231, Folder 2895)
    Nagle pumping engine
  - Prufrock Furniture Company (St. Louis, Mo.), 1906; Uai +P952; 1 volume (Box 254)
    Upholstered furniture
  - Public Buildings Supply Company, Inc. (New York, N.Y.), 1918; Uai P96; 1 volume (Box 231, Folder 2896)
    Brushes and sanitary supplies
  - Pullman Automatic Ventilator Manufacturing Company (York, Pa.), 1906; Uai P966; 1 volume (Box 231, Folder 2897)
    Pullman ventilation system
  - Pullman-Standard Car and Manufacturing Company (Chicago, Ill.), 1941; Uai +P9663; 1 volume (Box 255)
    "Tops" in streamliners
  - Pulsometer Steam Pump Company (New York, N.Y.), 1911; Uai P968; 1 volume (Box 231, Folder 2898)
    Pulsometers
  - Pure Oil Company (Chicago, Ill.), 1939–1943; Uai +P972; 2 volumes (Box 231, Folder 2899)
    Oils for diesel engines
  - Purina Mills (St. Louis, Mo.), 1942; Uai P973; 1 volume (Box 232, Folder 2900)
    Goats
  - Purinton, C. F., Company (South Easton, Mass.), undated; Uai P974; 1 volume (Box 232, Folder 2901)
    "Roll-a-way" window screens
  - Puro Sanitary Drinking Fountain Company (Haydenville, Mass.), 1930; Uai P975; 1 volume (Box 232, Folder 2902)
    Drinking fountains
  - Putnam Machine Company (Fitchburg, Mass.), 1877; Uai P984; 1 volume (Box 232, Folder 2903)
    Steam engines, machinists' tools, etc.
  - Pye, W. G., and Company (Cambridge, England), 1902–1926; Uai P992; 2 volumes (Box 232, Folder 2904-2905)
    Physical, physiological, and general scientific instruments
  - Pyrolectric Instrument Company (Trenton, N.J.), 1916–1921; Uai +P998; 1 volume (Box 232, Folder 2906)
    Pyrometric and electrical precision instruments
- Q
  - Q and C Company (New York, N.Y., Chicago, Ill.), 1914; Uai +Q11; 1 volume (Box 232, Folder 2907)
    Circulation system for locomotive boilers
  - Quaker City Chair Company (Richmond, Ind.), undated; Uai Q24; 1 volume (Box 232, Folder 2908)
    Chairs and rockers
  - Quaker City Metal Products Corporation, 1942; Uai +Q25; 1 volume (Box 232, Folder 2909)
    Radiator cabinets
  - Queen and Company (Philadelphia, Pa.), 1890–1892; Uai +Q32; 14 volumes (Box 232, Folder 2924)
  - Queen and Company, Inc. (Philadelphia, Pa.), 1893–1904; Uai +Q33; 16 volumes (Box 232, Folder 2925-2929)
  - Queen, James W., and Company (Philadelphia, Pa.), 1859–1892; Uai +Q31; 70 volumes (Box 232, Folder 2910-2923)
  - Quigley Furniture Company (Whitesboro, N.Y.), undated; Uai Q41; 1 volume (Box 232, Folder 2930)
  - Quimby, A. M. (New York, N.Y.), 1852; Uai Q42; 1 volume (Box 232, Folder 2931)
    Lightning rods
  - Quincy Show Case Works (Quincy, Ill.), 1910; Uai Q43; 1 volume (Box 232, Folder 2932)
    Display cases, furniture, etc.
  - Quinnipiac Company (Wallingford, Conn.), 1862; Uai Q44; 1 volume (Box 232, Folder 2933)
  - Quinnipiac Fertilizer Company (New London, Conn.), 1872–1881; Uai Q45; 3 volumes (Box 232, Folder 2934)
  - Quinnipiac Shirt Company (New Haven, Conn.), undated; Uai Q46; 1 volume (Box 232, Folder 2935)
    Dress shirts
- R
  - Racine Seating Company (Racine, Wis.), undated; Uai R115; 1 volume (Box 232, Folder 2936)
    Church furniture
  - Rack Engineering Company (Pittsburgh, Pa.), 1947; Uai R1155; 2 volumes (Box 232, Folder 2937)
    Industrial material handling equipment
  - Rademaker, H., and Sons (Grand Rapids, Mich.), 1912; Uai R117; 1 volume (Box 232, Folder 2938)
    Athletic equipment
  - Radio Component Manufacturers' Federation (London, England), 1946; Uai +R1178; 1 volume (Box 260)
    Radio components
  - Radio Corporation of America (Camden, N.J.), 1925–1939; Uai +R118; 7 volumes (Box 232, Folder 2939)
    Radio components, etc.
  - Radio Dealer Publishing Company, Inc. (New York, N.Y.), 1927; Uai R1183; 1 volume (Box 261)
    Resistors, etc.
  - Radio Receptor Company (New York, N.Y.), 1924; Uai R119; 1 volume (Box 232, Folder 2940)
    "Receptrad" radio supplies, etc.
  - Radio Shack Corporation (Boston, Mass.), 1949–1952; Uai R1193; 4 volumes (Box 232, Folder 2941-2942)
    Test equipment, transformers, etc.
  - Radio Wire Television Inc. (New York, N.Y.), undated; Uai R1195; 3 volumes (Box 257, Folder 2963)
    Radios and radio components, etc.
  - Railroad Supply Company (Chicago, Ill., New York, N.Y.), 1902; Uai R132; 1 volume (Box 257, Folder 2964)
    Oil purifier
  - Railway Utility Company (Chicago, Ill., etc.), 1919; Uai +R1327; 1 volume (Box 257, Folder 2965)
    Temperature control, ventilators, etc.
  - Rainbo Paper Favor Works (Chicago, Ill.), 1929–1938; Uai R134; 6 volumes (Box 257, Folder 2966-2967)
    Paper hats, novelties, etc.
  - Ralph, Wm., and Company (Utica, N.Y.), 1874; Uai R138; 2 volumes (Box 257, Folder 2968)
    Cheese factory and dairy apparatus, etc.
  - Ralston Purina Company (St. Louis, Mo.), 1933–1934; Uai +R139; 2 volumes (Box 257, Folder 2969)
    Rations for laboratory animals, etc.
  - Ramsey Chain Company, Inc. (Albany, N.Y.), undated; Uai +R146; 1 volume (Box 257, Folder 2970)
    Chains, sprockets, and couplings
  - Rand Drill Company (New York, N.Y.), 1886; Uai +R157; 1 volume (Box 257, Folder 2971)
    Rock drills, air compressors, etc.
  - Rand McNally and Company (Chicago, Ill., etc.), 1912–1917; Uai R158; 2 volumes (Box 257, Folder 2972)
    Office appliances, etc.
  - Randall-Faichney Company (Boston, Mass.), 1918; Uai R1585; 1 volume (Box 257, Folder 2973)
    Chemical thermometers
  - Randolph-Clowes Company (Waterbury, Conn.), 1911; Uai R159; 1 volume (Box 257, Folder 2974)
    Brass and copper tubing, tank shells, etc.
  - Rank, Amos, and Company (Canton, Ohio), 1868–1875; Uai R165; 2 volumes (Box 257, Folder 2975)
    Mowers and reapers, grave guards, etc.
  - Ransome Concrete Machinery (Dunellen, N.J.), 1937; Uai +R174; 2 volumes (Box 257, Folder 2976)
    Cement mixers, pavers, etc.
  - Ransomes and Sims (Ipswich, Suffolk, England), 1857–1867; Uai R1745; 3 volumes (Box 257, Folder 2977)
    Agricultural machinery
  - Ransomes, Sims and Head (Ipswich and London, England), 1878; Uai R1746; 3 volumes (Box 257, Folder 2978)
  - Rattan Manufacturing Company (New Haven, Conn.), 1900–1909; Uai +R178; 10 volumes (Box 257, Folder 2979-2984)
    Carriages, invalid chairs, etc.
  - Rau, William H. (Philadelphia, Pa.), 1886; Uai R18; 1 volume (Box 257, Folder 2985)
  - Rauch and Lang Carriage Company (Cleveland, Ohio), 1914; Uai R19; 1 volume (Box 257, Folder 2986)
    Electric automobiles
  - Rawiszer, J. (New York, N.Y.), 1889; Uai R198; 1 volume (Box 257, Folder 2988)
    Medals, badges, etc.
  - Rawlings Manufacturing Company (New York, N.Y.), 1926–1928; Uai +R199; 5 volumes (Box 257, Folder 2989)
  - Rawlings Sporting Goods Company (St. Louis, Mo.), 1902–1905; Uai +R1994; 5 volumes (Box 257, Folder 2990-2994)
  - Raybestos-Manhattan, Inc. (Manheim, Pa., etc.), 1940; Uai +R211; 1 volume (Box 257, Folder 2995)
    Asbestos textiles and textile products
  - Raynor, H. M. (New York, N.Y.), undated; Uai +R218; 1 volume (Box 257, Folder 2996)
    Multi-use platinum sheet and wire, etc.
  - Read, D. M. Company (Bridgeport, Conn.), 1923; Uai R221; 1 volume (Box 257, Folder 2997)
    Trunks and bags
  - Read, William, and Sons (Boston, Mass.), 1895; Uai +R222; 4 volumes (Box 257, Folder 2998)
    Arms and military supplies
  - Read, William, and Sons (Boston, Mass.), 1886–1905; 19 volumes (Box 399, Folder 4342-4346)
  - Readex Microprint Corporation (New York, N.Y.), 1940; Uai R225; 1 volume (Box 257, Folder 2999)
    Readex microprints
  - Reading Chain Block Company (Reading, Pa.), 1913; Uai R226; 1 volume (Box 257, Folder 3000)
    Chain blocks, trolleys, etc.
  - Reading Hardware Company (Reading, Pa.), Uai +R227
    Builders' hardware, art hardware, etc.
    - 1877, 1 volume (Box 262)
    - 1905, 1 volume (Box 263)
  - Reading Iron Company (Reading, Pa.), 1917; Uai R2275; 1 volume (Box 257, Folder 3001)
    Vanishing-thread joint, etc.
  - Reading Standard Manufacturing Company (Reading, Pa.), 1898–1902; Uai R2279; 4 volumes (Box 257, Folder 3002)
  - Ready Made Sign Company (New York, N.Y.), undated; Uai +R2281; 1 volume (Box 257, Folder 3003)
    Road signs
  - Ready Tool Company (Bridgeport, Conn.), undated; Uai +R2282; 2 volumes (Box 257, Folder 3004)
  - Recording Fare Register Company (New Haven, Conn.), 1905–1906; Uai +R245; 2 volumes (Box 257, Folder 3005)
    Fare registers and electric railroad supplies
  - Redding, Baird and Company (Boston, Mass.), 1905; Uai R247; 1 volume (Box 257, Folder 3006)
    Stained glass and leaded glass windows
  - Reed and Barton (Taunton, Mass.), 1926; Uai +R252; 4 volumes (Box 257, Folder 3008-3009)
  - Reed and Carnick (Jersey City, N.J.), 1903–1917; Uai R2522; 2 volumes (Box 257, Folder 3010)
    Medical preparations, tonics, antiseptics, etc.
  - Reed's, Jacob, Sons (Philadelphia, Pa.), undated; Uai +R253; 1 volume (Box 257, Folder 3011)
  - Reed, Dr. A., Cushion Shoe Company (New York, N.Y.), undated; Uai R251; 1 volume (Box 257, Folder 3007)
  - Reeves Pulley Company (Columbus, Ohio), 1943; Uai +R2592; 2 volumes (Box 257, Folder 3013)
    Transmissions, motor drives, etc.
  - Reeves, Robert C. (New York, N.Y.), 1867–1870; Uai +R259; 3 volumes (Box 257, Folder 3012)
    Agricultural cutters
  - Refrigerating Specialties Company (Chicago, Ill.), 1939; Uai +R2596; 1 volume (Box 257, Folder 3014)
    Refrigerating machinery, etc.
  - Regal Motor Car Company (Detroit, Mich.), 1910; Uai R26; 2 volumes (Box 257, Folder 3015)
  - Reichardt, F. Alfred and Company (New York, N.Y.), undated; Uai R270; 1 volume (Box 257, Folder 3016)
  - Reichert, Carl (Vienna, Austria), 1888–1893; Uai R271; 2 volumes (Box 257, Folder 3017)
  - Reid Portable Oven Company (Buffalo, N.Y.), undated; Uai R273; 1 volume (Box 257, Folder 3020)
    Ovens
  - Reid and Sons (Newcastle-Upon-Tyne, England), 1927; Uai +R2725; 1 volume (Box 257, Folder 3019)
  - Reid, Adam (Buffalo, N.Y.), 1885; Uai +R272; 4 volumes (Box 257, Folder 3018)
    Ovens and vases
  - Reimann, L. (Berlin, Germany), 1851; Uai +R2745; 1 volume (Box 257, Folder 3021)
    Scales, etc.
  - Reinmann and Baetz (New York, N.Y.), 1878; Uai R276; 1 volume (Box 257, Folder 3022)
    Chemical and physical glass instruments
  - Relay Manufacturing Company, Ltd. (Reading, Pa.), 1893; Uai R278; 1 volume (Box 257, Folder 3023)
    "Relay" bicycles
  - Reliable Incubator and Brooder Company (Quincy, Ill.), 1911; Uai R279; 1 volume (Box 257, Folder 3024)
  - Reliance Electric and Engineering Company (Cleveland, Ohio), 1928–1930; Uai +R2795; 6 volumes (Box 257, Folder 3025)
    Motors, etc.
  - Reliance Manufacturing Company (Massillon, Ohio), 1913; Uai R28; 1 volume (Box 257, Folder 3026)
  - Reltool Corporation (Milwaukee, Wis.), undated; Uai R282; 1 volume (Box 257, Folder 3027)
    Metal cutting tools
  - Remington Arms Company (New York, N.Y.), 1894–1900; Uai R284; 5 volumes (Box 257, Folder 3028)
  - Remington Rand Business Service, Inc. (Buffalo, N.Y.), 1928–1943; Uai +R2844; 7 volumes (Box 264)
    Typewriters, record equipment, etc.
  - Remington Typewriter Company, Inc. (New York, N.Y.), 1918–1921; Uai R2486; 2 volumes (Box 257, Folder 3029)
  - Rendle, Arthur E. (New York, N.Y.), 1900; Uai +R292; 1 volume (Box 257, Folder 3030)
    Skylights and sheet metal work
  - Repel-Arc Furnace Company (Indianapolis, Ind.), 1921; Uai +R299; 1 volume (Box 257, Folder 3031)
    Electric furnaces
  - Republic Iron and Steel Company (Pittsburg, Pa.), 1911; Uai R31; 1 volume (Box 265)
    Steel and iron products
  - Republic Service Division (New York, N.Y.), undated; Uai +R311; 2 volumes (Box 257, Folder 3032)
    Twist drills, reamers, cutters, etc.
  - Republic Steel Corporation (Cleveland, Ohio), 1941–1942; Uai +R312; 2 volumes (Box 257, Folder 3033)
    Stainless steel tubing and goods
  - Resale, 1951; Uai R315; 1 volume (Box 333)
    Machine tools, etc.
  - Reuther, Wilton, Company (Detroit, Mich.), 1905; Uai +R318; 1 volume (Box 257, Folder 3034)
    Art goods and special furniture
  - Revere Copper and Brass Incorporated (New York, N.Y.), 1944; Uai +R324; 1 volume (Box 257, Folder 3035)
    Copper and copper alloys
  - Revolute Machine Company (New York, N.Y.), 1914; Uai R328; 1 volume (Box 257, Folder 3036)
    Blue print machinery
  - Reynolds Metals Company, Inc. (Louisville, Ky.), 1947; Uai +R3395; 1 volume (Box 258, Folder 3037)
    Aluminum goods
  - Rhenish Glass Company (Cologne-Ehrenfeld, Germany), 1910; Uai +R343; 1 volume (Box 258, Folder 3038)
    Rhenish apparatus glass
  - Rhode Island Locomotive Works (Providence, R.I.), 1925; Uai R346; 2 volumes (Box 258, Folder 3039-3040)
    Locomotive and tramway engines
  - Rice and Whitacre Manufacturing Company (Chicago, Ill.), 1892; Uai R368; 1 volume (Box 258, Folder 3042)
  - Rice, William E., Company (Boston, Mass.), 1914; Uai R367; 1 volume (Box 258, Folder 3041)
    Tape, glue, paste, labels, etc.
  - Richards and Company (New York, N.Y.), 1878–1886; Uai R391; 6 volumes (Box 258, Folder 3044-3045)
  - Richards and Sencenbaugh Manufacturing Company (Aurora, Ill.), 1905; Uai R3911; 1 volume (Box 258, Folder 3046)
    Door hangers and hardware specialties
  - Richards, A., and Company (Guilford, Conn.), 1889; Uai R39; 1 volume (Box 258, Folder 3043)
    Combined glue and cement
  - Richards, Hand and Taylor (Philadelphia, Pa.), undated; Uai R3913; 1 volume (Box 258, Folder 3047)
    Standard gauges
  - Richards, London and Kelley (Philadelphia, Pa., etc.), 1876; Uai R3914; 1 volume (Box 266)
    Sawing machinery
  - Richardson Reflector Company, Inc. (New York, N.Y.), 1939; Uai +R396; 1 volume (Box 258, Folder 3049)
    Picture reflectors, flood lights, etc.
  - Richardson and Boynton Company (Chicago, Ill., etc.), 1889; Uai +R395; 3 volumes (Box 258, Folder 3048)
    Hot water heater
  - Richmond Bicycle Company (Richmond, Ind.), undated; Uai R4142; 2 volumes (Box 258, Folder 3051)
  - Richmond Sod Cutter Company (Richmond, Ind.), undated; Uai R414; 1 volume (Box 258, Folder 3050)
    Sod cutters
  - Richmond Stove Company (Norwich, Conn.), 1905–1906; Uai +R4145; 4 volumes (Box 258, Folder 3052)
    Stoves and boilers
  - Richmond Vehicle Company (Richmond, Va.), 1904; Uai R4147; 1 volume (Box 258, Folder 3053)
  - Ricker and Montgomery (Rochester, N.Y.), 1891; Uai R422; 1 volume (Box 258, Folder 3054)
    Hay carriers and slings
  - Rider Engine Company (New York, N.Y., Chicago, Ill.), undated; Uai R435; 1 volume (Box 258, Folder 3055)
    Hot air pumping machines
  - Rider, Wooster and Company (Walden, N.Y.), 1877; Uai R4356; 1 volume (Box 258, Folder 3056)
    Pumping engines
  - Ridgway Furnace Company (Boston, Mass.), 1896; Uai R436; 1 volume (Box 258, Folder 3057)
    Open fire pot heater or furnace
  - Riehlé Brothers' Philadelphia Scale and Testing Machine Works (Philadelphia, Pa.), 1879–1887; Uai +R444; 8 volumes (Box 258, Folder 3058-3061)
    Testing machinery, etc.
  - Riehlé Brothers' Testing Machine Company (Philadelphia, Pa.), 1927; Uai +R4441; 5 volumes (Box 258, Folder 3062)
  - Riesick, P. (Allegheny, Pa.), 1898–1905; Uai +R446; 2 volumes (Box 258, Folder 3063)
    Joist hangers, structural iron works, etc.
  - Rife's Hydraulic Engine Manufacturing Company (Roanoke, Va., etc.), 1892; Uai R448; 1 volume (Box 258, Folder 3064)
    Hydraulic engines
  - Rigg, James (London, England), 1895; Uai +R449; 1 volume (Box 258, Folder 3065)
    Rigg's technical education appliances
  - Riker's Drug Store (New York, N.Y.), undated; Uai R4495; 1 volume (Box 258, Folder 3066)
  - Riley Optical Instrument Company (New York, N.Y.), 1906–1907; Uai R454; 1 volume (Box 258, Folder 3067)
    Optical lantern works accessories and supplies
  - Rinald Brothers (Philadelphia, Pa.), 1898–1899; Uai R47; 2 volumes (Box 258, Folder 3068)
    Porcelain enamel paint
  - Ripley-Sanford Company (Hartford, Conn.), undated; Uai +R482; 1 volume (Box 258, Folder 3069)
    Plaster, papier mache, ornaments, etc.
  - Ritchie, E. S., and Sons (Boston, Mass.), 1868–1896; Uai R5111; 10 volumes (Box 258, Folder 3072-3076)
    Philosophical apparatus
  - Ritchie, Edward S. (Boston, Mass.), 1857–1860; Uai R511; 2 volumes (Box 258, Folder 3070-3071)
  - Ritter Dental Manufacturing Company, Inc. (Rochester, N.Y.), 1922; Uai R514; 1 volume (Box 258, Folder 3078)
    Enamels and finishes
  - Ritter-Carlton Company, Inc. (New York, N.Y.), 1939; Uai R513; 1 volume (Box 258, Folder 3077)
  - Rivett Lathe Manufacturing Company (Boston, Mass.), undated; Uai R525; 2 volumes (Box 258, Folder 3079-3080)
  - Rixson, Oscar C., Company (Chicago, Ill.), 1914–1918; Uai R528; 3 volumes (Box 258, Folder 3081-3082)
    Hardware specialties
  - Robbins Company (Attleboro, Mass.), 1920; Uai +R538; 1 volume (Box 258, Folder 3083)
    Trophies
  - Robertson, W., Machine and Foundry Company (Buffalo, N.Y.), undated; Uai R546; 4 volumes (Box 258, Folder 3084)
    Power saw machinery
  - Robey and Company (Lincoln, England, etc.), 1878; Uai R548; 1 volume (Box 258, Folder 3085)
    Steam engines, mills, farm and sawing machinery
  - Robins Life Guard and Manufacturing Company (Philadelphia, Pa.), 1894; Uai R558; 1 volume (Box 258, Folder 3086)
    Safety fender for street cars
  - Robinson Chilled Plow Company (Syracuse, N.Y.), 1877; Uai +R568; 1 volume (Box 258, Folder 3088)
  - Robinson, John and Company, Ltd. (Bristol, England), 1938; Uai R563; 1 volume (Box 258, Folder 3087)
    Oil mills
  - Rochester Camera Company (Rochester, N.Y.), 1897–1899; Uai R585; 1 volume (Box 258, Folder 3089)
    Photographic apparatus
  - Rochester Can Company (Rochester, N.Y.), 1939; Uai +R5852; 2 volumes (Box 258, Folder 3090)
    "Iron Horse" metal ware
  - Rochester Cycle Manufacturing Company (Rochester, N.Y.), 1901; Uai R5854; 1 volume (Box 258, Folder 3091)
  - Rochester Optical Company (Rochester, N.Y.), 1899; Uai R586; 1 volume (Box 258, Folder 3092)
    "Premo" camera
  - Rochester Optical and Camera Company (Rochester, N.Y.), 1906; Uai R5861; 2 volumes (Box 258, Folder 3093)
    "Premo" camera, Dry plates
  - Rocholl, Franz (New York, N.Y.), 1877; Uai R589; 1 volume (Box 258, Folder 3094)
    Toys and fancy goods
  - Rockwell Furnacy Company (New York, N.Y.), 1909; Uai +R595; 1 volume (Box 267)
  - Rockwood Manufacturing Company (Indianapolis, Ind.), 1943; Uai +R598; 1 volume (Box 268)
    Belt drives
  - Roe, Justus, and Sons (New York, N.Y., Patchogue, N.Y.), 1887–1888; Uai R62; 2 volumes (Box 258, Folder 3095)
    Engineering and mathematical instruments, steel tape, reels, etc.
  - Roebling Construction Company (New York, N.Y.), 1899; Uai R6211; 1 volume (Box 258, Folder 3096)
    Roebling concrete system and tile construction
  - Roebling's, John A., Sons Company (New York, N.Y., etc.), 1897–1919; Uai R6212; 3 volumes (Box 258, Folder 3097-3098)
    Wire rope and wire
  - Rogers Jr., Joseph, and Son (Farmingdale, N.J.), 1940; Uai R632; 1 volume (Box 258, Folder 3102)
    Drums
  - Rogers and Hubbard Company (Middletown, Conn.), 1941; Uai R6332; 2 volumes (Box 259, Folder 3103)
  - Rogers, Brown and Company (New York, N.Y.), 1915; Uai R6336; 1 volume (Box 259, Folder 3104)
    Pig iron and coke, etc.
  - Rogers, C., and Brothers (West Meriden, Conn.), 1876; Uai R6312; 1 volume (Box 258, Folder 3099)
    Casket trimmings
  - Rogers, Charles P., and Company (New York, N.Y.), 1907–1909; Uai R6314; 3 volumes (Box 258, Folder 3100-3101)
    Brass and iron bedsteads, etc.
  - Rogers, Lunt and Bowlen Company (Greenfield, Mass.), 1929–1930; Uai R6339; 2 volumes (Box 259, Folder 3105)
  - Rogers, Smith and Company (New Haven, Conn.), Uai +R6346
    Silver plated goods
    - 1867, 1 volume (Box 269)
    - 1868–1873, 4 volumes (Box 270, Folder 3161-3165)
    - 1879, 1 volume (Box 271)
  - Rogers, Smith and Company (New Haven, Conn.), 1873; 1 volume (Box 404)
    Heavily plated goods
  - Rohm and Haas Company (Philadelphia, Pa.), 1949; Uai +R635; 2 volumes (Box 259, Folder 3106-3107)
    Resins, Plexiglas, etc.
  - Rohrbeck and Goebeler (New York, N.Y.), 1871; Uai R6362; 3 volumes (Box 259, Folder 3111)
    Chemical instruments and apparatus, etc.
  - Rohrbeck, Dr. Hermann (Berlin, Germany), undated; Uai +R636; 2 volumes (Box 259, Folder 3108-3109)
  - Rohrbeck, W. J. (Berlin, Germany, etc.), 1861; Uai R6361; 1 volume (Box 259, Folder 3110)
  - Rolls-Royce Limited (London, England), 1937; Uai +R659; 2 volumes (Box 259, Folder 3112-3113)
    Rolls-Royce automobiles
  - Roof, W. S., and Company (Franklin, Ohio), 1905; Uai R672; 1 volume (Box 259, Folder 3114)
    Sliding and folding door and partition hangers
  - Rooker, John (London, England), 1831; Uai R674; 1 volume (Box 259, Folder 3115)
    Pocket calculator
  - Root, A. I., Company (Medina, Ohio), 1919; Uai R6778; 1 volume (Box 259, Folder 3116)
    Beekeepers' supplies
  - Root, C. J., Company (Bristol, Conn.), 1908–1916; Uai R678; 2 volumes (Box 259, Folder 3117)
    Counting machines
  - Roots, P. H. and F. M., Company (Connersville, Ind.), 1876–1926; Uai +R679; 4 volumes (Box 259, Folder 3118-3119)
  - Rosemary Incorporated (New York, N.Y.), 1938; Uai R722; 1 volume (Box 259, Folder 3120)
    Table linen
  - Rosenbach Company (Philadelphia, Pa.), 1938; Uai R723; 1 volume (Box 259, Folder 3121)
    Reproductions of antique furniture, etc.
  - Ross Heater and Manufacturing Company, Inc. (Buffalo, N.Y.), 1917; Uai R7336; 1 volume (Box 259, Folder 3126)
    Heater and expansion joint
  - Ross and Company (London, England), 1875–1895; Uai +R7331; 4 volumes (Box 259, Folder 3125)